lonestarlearning.com 2019-06-16

# 

Privacy Policy

Updated June 2016

This privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) tells you about the information that Lone Star Learning Sales and Marketing, Inc (“LSL,” “we” or “our”) collects in connection with the operation of its Lone Star Learning website, (the “Site,” which consists of all content and pages located within the lonestarlearning.com web domain).

This Privacy Policy only applies to information that we collect through the Site and does not apply to information that we may collect from you in other ways (for example, this policy does not apply to information that you may provide to us over the phone, by fax or through conventional mail). In addition, please note that your education records are protected by the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (“FERPA”) to the extent FERPA applies.

YOUR ACCEPTANCE OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND REVISIONS TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

By using the Site, you agree to this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, you may not use the Site. LSL reserves the right, in our discretion, to change, modify, add or remove portions of this Privacy Policy from time to time, without prior notice to you. All revisions will be posted to the Site. By accessing the Site after any changes have been made, you signify your agreement on a prospective basis to the modified Privacy Policy and any changes contained therein. Be sure to return to this page periodically to ensure familiarity with the most current version of this Privacy Policy.

PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION

As used in this Privacy Policy, Personally Identifiable Information (“PII”) means any information about yourself that you may provide to us when using the Site, such as when you sign up for a user account, which may include (but is not limited to) your name and contact information. We endeavor to limit the collection of PII to what we need with respect to specific Site activities in order to satisfy business, legal, or regulatory requirements.

Contact form submission data ó IP address, user agent, name, email address, website, and message ó is submitted to the Akismet service (owned by Automattic) for the sole purpose of spam checking. The actual submission data is stored in the database of the site on which it was submitted and is emailed directly to the owner of the form (i.e. the site author who published the page on which the contact form resides). This email will include the submitterís IP address, timestamp, name, email address, website, and message.

Data Synced: Post and post meta data associated with a userís contact form submission. If Akismet is enabled on the site, the IP address and user agent originally submitted with the comment are synced, as well, as they are stored in post meta. Purchase events will send Google Analytics the following information: order number, product id and name, product category, total cost, and quantity of items purchased.

Data Used: When sharing content via ShareThis or email, the following information is used: sharing partyís name and email address (if the user is logged in, this information will be pulled directly from their account), IP address (for spam checking), user agent (for spam checking), and email body/content. This content will be sent to Akismet (also owned by Automattic) so that a spam check can be performed. 

INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND HOW WE USE IT

We collect information, including PII (described above), when you sign up for a user account and/or send us email messages. 

As a custodian of PII, LSL complies with the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA), to the extent FERPA applies, in its handling of education records. Upon termination or cancellation of a Customer contract, LSL will delete all PII data from its records. LSL may retain aggregate, non-identifying usage information for the purpose of reporting, analytics, and improving LSL's products and services.

Upon our collection of your PII, LSL may use such information internally, separately or in combination with pre-existing information, for the following purposes:

To provide any requested services;

To troubleshoot problems with the Site, or any services, as requested;

To improve our products;

To customize your experience, content or homepage on the Site;

To enforce our Terms of Use;

To generate aggregate statistical studies and conduct research; or

To provide any legitimate business service or product.

COOKIES

Cookies help us in many ways to make your use of the Site more enjoyable and meaningful, such as understanding usage patterns and improving functionality of the Site. Cookies are text information files that your web browser places on your computer when you use a website. LSL may use such “cookie” technology to obtain non-personal information from you.

LSL uses analytics tools and other third party technologies, such as Google Analytics Display Advertising  ([Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2799357?hl=en)) and DoubleClick Cookies, to collect non-personal information in the form of various usage and user metrics when you use our online Sites and/or Services. These tools and technologies collect and analyze certain types of information, including cookies, IP addresses, device and software identifiers, referring and exit URLs, onsite behavior and usage information, feature use metrics and statistics, usage and purchase history, MAC Address, mobile unique device ID, and other similar information. You can [opt-out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/) of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads using the Ads Settings. In addition, you can use the [Google Analytics Opt-Out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/) to disable tracking by Google Analytics. LSL relies on the data provided by Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting to develop the site and content around our users’ interests. 

Third party analytics companies like DoubleClick who collect information on LSL Sites and/or Services and other online products and/or services may combine the information collected with other information they have independently collected from other websites and/or other online or mobile products and services relating to your activities across their network of websites as well as online and/or mobile products and services. Many of these companies collect and use information under their own privacy policies. You may opt out of the DoubleClick cookie by visiting the Google advertising opt-out page or you may opt out of Google Analytics by visiting the Google Analytics opt-out page.

DATA SHARING AND TRANSFER

LSL will provide data and the personal identifiable information on users and the analysis of trends for all users on an aggregate basis to some or all of the following (collectively, the “Customer”): the LSL, a user’s school district, or a user’s school. LSL provides such information as a service to its Customer but it does not control the use of such data after it provides it to the Customer. Consequently, LSL takes no responsibility or liability for the use of such data after it provides it to the Customer.

LSL does not provide, sell or lend any personally identifiable information to any third party.

LSL reserves the right to disclose your personally identifiable information based on the good faith belief that such action is necessary or appropriate to: (a) protect and defend the rights or property of LSL, or (b) act in urgent circumstances to protect the safety or security of the public or of users of LSL’s services and/or the Site.

Your personal information will generally be stored in LSL’s databases, which are located in the United States. Our policy is to ensure that your information is always granted the same level of protection no matter where it is stored.

LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES

The Site contains links to websites published by third parties, including other content providers. These other websites are not under our control, and you acknowledge and agree that we are not responsible for the collection and use of your information by such websites, unless we have otherwise indicated in this Privacy Policy. We encourage you to be aware when you are be redirected to a third party website and review the privacy policies of each website you visit and use.

SECURITY

LSL has a program designed to protect PII in its possession or control. This is done through a variety of privacy and security policies, processes, and procedures, including administrative, physical, and technical safeguards that reasonably and appropriately protect the confidentiality, security, and availability of the PII that it creates, receives, maintains, or transmits. While the security of users’ PII is of the utmost importance to LSL, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure; and therefore, LSL cannot guarantee its absolute security.

PAYMENT

LSL uses Square and PayPal to process and accept the payment-related information that they receive as necessary and appropriate to fulfill requests to process payment transactions, to facilitate billing, and to otherwise deliver payment services. Personally identifiable information about consumers is used by Square or PayPal to process payment transactions and for no other purpose. Square’s full privacy policy can be viewed [here](https://squareup.com/legal/privacy-no-account). PayPal's full privacy policy can be viewed [here](https://www.paypal.com/cg/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full).

Square and PayPal all adhere to international PCI (payment card industry) compliance standards for data security. When payment is accepted directly by LSL, all credit card information is destroyed after processing.

Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS) is a set of 12 requirements that all businesses who handle credit or debit card payments must comply with. The PCI Security Standards require all merchants, regardless of size or number of transactions, who accept, store, transmit or process any cardholder data to comply with PCI DSS. You can find out more about PCI [here](https://www.pcisecuritystandards.org/). 

PRIVACY CONCERNS

If you have privacy concerns, have disclosed data you would prefer to keep private, or would like to access the information we maintain about you, please contact us at 1-800-575-1424 or by mail at P.O. Box 6066 Lubbock TX 79493
